bicycleretailer.com 2019-12-18

# Pocket Outdoor MediaPrivacy Policy |

**Privacy Policy**

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Statement of Privacy applies to podiumrunner.com, pocketoutdoormedia.com, triathlete.com, velonews.com, velopress.com, veloswap.com, womensrunning.com, and any other affiliated websites of Pocket Outdoor Media and governs data collection and usage. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to Pocket Outdoor Media or “POM” include podiumrunner.com, pocketoutdoormedia.com, triathlete.com, velonews.com, velopress.com, veloswap.com, and womensrunning.com. The POM websites are news and information sites. By using the POM websites, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of your Personal Information**

We do not collect any personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us. However, you may be required to provide certain personal information to us when you elect to use certain products or services available on the Sites. These may include: (a) registering for an account on our Sites; (b) entering a sweepstakes or contest sponsored by us or one of our partners; (c) signing up for special offers from selected third parties; (d) sending us an email message; (e) submitting your credit card or other payment information when ordering an purchasing products and services on our Sites; (f) responding to surveys. To wit, we will use your information for, but not limited to, communicating with you in relation to services and/or products you have requested from us. We also may gather additional personal or non-personal information in the future.

In order to better provide you with products and services offered on our Sites, POM may collect personally identifiable information, such as your:

  * Name
  * Mailing Address
  * E-mail Address
  * Phone Number

If you purchase POM’s products and services, we collect billing and credit card information. This information is used to complete the purchase transaction.

POM may also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your:

  * Age
  * Gender
  * Race
  * Household Income

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through POM’s public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. You are responsible for deleting any information you release on our public message boards.

**Use of your Personal Information**

POM collects and uses your personal information to operate its website(s) and deliver the services you have requested.

POM may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from POM, its affiliates, and our partners.

**Sharing Information with Third Parties**

POM’s standard practice is to share as little of your personal information as possible. We reserve the right to share, sell, rent, or lease customer information to third parties for advertising purposes and to acquire users and subscribers, as allowed by law.

In order to deliver the products or services you have requested from us, it is necessary for POM to share your personal information with our trusted third-party vendors and partners. POM may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of third-party business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) may be transferred to a third party.

POM may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. For example, in order to send you our free e-mail newsletters, we must process your information using a trusted e-mail newsletter service vendor like MailChimp. In order to mail you magazines to which you subscribe, we must share your personal information with our magazine fulfillment partner.

All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to POM, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. At the termination of a contract with a third-party business partner or vendor and subject to the terms of the contract, the partner or vendor will delete user information. POM is not responsible for third-party vendor non-compliance.

The only way to completely stop all sharing of your personal information is to terminate your relationship with POM and its brands, which will cause us to delete all your personal information from our databases and request deletion of your information from our third-party partner databases. After you terminate your relationship with us, you will no longer receive products or services that you have requested or purchased from us. We do not offer refunds for products or services not completely fulfilled at the time we receive your relationship termination request. To request deletion from our system, please contact our data privacy staff person using the contact information below.

POM may disclose your personal information, without notice, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on POM or the sites; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of POM; and/or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of POM, or the public.

**Tracking User Behavior**

POM may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within POM, in order to determine what POM services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within POM to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

We may also collect information about you from third parties like social media platforms, some of which may be personally identifiable information. We combine information about our online users and our subscribers with information we collect about you through other means. This data profiling allows us to continue to provide goods and services to you.

**Automatically Collected Information**

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by POM. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring websites addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the POM websites.

**Use of Cookies**

The POM websites may use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize POM pages, or register with POM sites or services, a cookie helps POM to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same POM websites, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the POM features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the POM services or websites you visit. Your browser may also allow you to delete cookies.

**Links**

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our sites and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

**Children Under Thirteen**

POM does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website.

**Opt-Out & Unsubscribe from Third Party Communications**

We respect your privacy and give you an opportunity to opt-out of receiving announcements of certain information. Users may opt out of receiving all e-mail communications from third-party partners of POM by unsubscribing from our e-mail lists. Making this change means you will no longer receive our free e-mail newsletters. After you are unsubscribed, we may continue to contact you so that we may provide customer service for products and services you have requested or purchased.

**E-mail Communications**

From time to time, POM may contact you via email for the purpose of providing announcements, promotional offers, alerts, confirmations, surveys, and/or other general communication.

We use MailChimp as our marketing automation platform. When submitting forms and/or subscribing to our newsletters, you acknowledge that the information you provide will be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/).

If you would like to stop receiving marketing or promotional communications via email from POM, you may easily opt out of such communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link that appears at the bottom of every email we send to our newsletter list members.

**External Data Storage Sites**

We may store your data on servers provided by third-party hosting vendors with whom we have contracted. We make every reasonable effort to assure that our contracts with vendors include requirements for those vendors to use industry standard best practices to keep your data secure. POM is not responsible for third-party vendor non-compliance or data breaches.

**Changes to this Statement**

POM reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account, by placing a prominent notice on our site, and/or by updating any privacy information on this page. Your continued use of the Sites and/or Services available through this Site after such modifications will constitute your: (a) acknowledgment of the modified Privacy Policy; and (b) agreement to abide and be bound by that Policy.

**_GDPR Policies for EU Citizens in the EU_**

Unless otherwise barred by law, all disputes will be resolved under the laws of the state of Colorado and the United States of America. EU citizens may file any complaints about our privacy policy or terms of service with their relevant governing body.

Your information may be required in order for us to deliver the good or service you have purchased from us or for you to enjoy goods, information, or services provided by us without purchase. If you request to change or delete your information, this may cause us to become unable to provide our goods and services to you. Our terms of service govern how we will resolve these conflicts.

We keep your information for as long as is necessary to continue providing you with our goods or services or for as long as we believe that you may wish to receive our goods or services in the future. We may delete your information at any time at our discretion and without notice.

Our data protection officer is Ilana Coenen. Through our data protection officer, EU citizens may request a record of their information, change or update their information, or request the deletion of their information. We will respond to your request within one month of receiving your request.

**Contact Information**

POM welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that POM has not adhered to this Statement, please contact POM at:

Pocket Outdoor Media  
4745 Walnut St., Unit A  
Boulder, Colorado 80301

Email Address: icoenen@pocketoutdoormedia.com

First published October 26, 2017. Updated to comply with GDPR in May, 2018. Updated on July 2, 2019 and December 16, 2019.
